Ethan Frigon

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

ethan.frigon@gmail.com

508-846-7233

Los Angeles, CA

GitHub LinkedIn

Portfolio

Skilled fullstack developer who's built several applications in the MERN stack and is always excited to learn new technologies. Team player with experience at companies both large and small who quickly gets the lay of the land and adds value immediately. Away from the monitor, an avid cyclist, occasional brewer, and huge basketball fan. Excited to join a team of intelligent, thoughtful developers who strive to get things done.

SKILLS

Advanced: JavaScript, ES6, React, Redux, Node.js, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, NPM, REST APIs

Proficient: PostgreSQL, jQuery, Sass, Python, TDD with Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, and Enzyme

Expert: Written & verbal communication, project management, customer experience

EXPERIENCE

RECENT PROJECTS
Full Stack Developer

Los Angeles, CA January 2019-Present

DOWNTHEBLOCK

- Engineered geolocation-based forums and direct messaging using React, Redux, and Socket.IO, enabling users to post and chat with nearby neighbors in real time
- Architected a RESTful Node API with an Express framework to process accounts, posts, comments, and messages in a MongoDB database
- Implemented Sass to design a clean, responsive interface with an intuitive user experience
- Utilized JWT-based authentication that assigns and validates JSON Web Tokens to persist user sessions, using bcrypt.js and Passport.js to encrypt and retrieve passwords

SPANISHX

- Engineered quiz-based front-end using React with Redux, serving users Spanish words to facilitate learning
- Architected a RESTful Node API with an Express framework to process user input
- Created and implemented a server-side algorithm based on the concept of spaced repetition to display new words to the user based on past answer history
- Utilized JWT-based authentication that assigns and validates JSON Web Tokens to persist user sessions, using bcrypt.js and Passport.js to encrypt and retrieve passwords

VACATIONBRAIN

- Created React and Redux based front-end, enabling users to ask for and provide travel recommendations to the VacationBrain community
- Architected a RESTful Node API with an Express framework to process trips, suggestions, and users in a MongoDB database
- Utilized JWT-based authentication that assigns and validates JSON Web Tokens to persist user sessions, using bcrypt.js and Passport.js to encrypt and retrieve passwords

JAZVA

Implementation Specialist

Los Angeles, CA

January-September 2018

 Onboarded new ecommerce clients of all sizes (from one-person businesses to daily multi-million dollar sales operations)

- Analyzed client's current business processes to find improvements and determine best course of implementation
- Analyzed and migrated client product and sales data, including third-party extensions to marketplaces, direct sales websites, and accounting software
- Scoped and owned roadmap items on behalf of the Product team for any additional client requests (custom software options, EDI implementations, etc.)
- Trained clients at all stakeholder levels (from founders to warehouse workers) on usage of full suite of software

STARTENGINE Los Angeles, CA

Customer Research Manager

September 2017-January 2018

- Owned all research efforts to identify new companies eligible to list on the StartEngine equity crowdfunding platform, a mix of individual company research and contractor management.
- Wrote and A/B tested email subject lines, content, and copy to drive identified companies down the sales funnel.
- Managed and produced weekly workshop with Business Development team, driving attendance via email strategy
- Tested and deployed new email delivery tools for better deliverability and to align with company strategy

THE WALL STREET JOURNAL

New York, NY & Los Angeles, CA

July 2015-July 2017

Customer Experience Architect

- Used customer journey maps to define the optimal customer experience across new digital product launches for the WSJ What's News and WSJ City iOS and Android apps
- Worked with Sales teams to define and explain new technological solutions in language that makes sense for clients
- Mapped customer journeys to identify and define opportunities for improvement within existing products (WSJ, Barron's, Financial News) across all customer touchpoints
- Worked across Product, Marketing, Customer Service, and Technology departments to estimate impact of and implement improvement opportunities

Training and Operations Specialist

July 2013-July 2015

- Maintained and migrated a customer service knowledge base containing 1000+ articles, which was used by all business groups within the department, to a new platform
- Managed total reorganization of knowledge base to create easier navigation and discovery for reps, and to better track usage using Google Analytics

EDUCATION

TUFTS UNIVERSITY

BA, Economics and International Relations

May 2011

THINKFUL March 2019

Engineering Immersion

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, and algorithms & data structures.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.